all right here we go
ready start
recording
okay let's talk about starlink but more
importantly let's talk about what is
pushing starlink to improve and be
better so let me turn the camera around
so you can watch this and I can drive
safely while we're talking so today I
learned about something that some of you
may already know it's called project
Kyper I think I said it right Kyper it
starts with a K and it's from Amazon so
Amazon has been quietly launching a
starling competitor for several years
and has got uh a lot of stuff already
done about it they published information
about the three different types of
dishes they have which we're going to
talk about in a second and they are
destined hey speaking of Amazon there's
Amazon Prime truck what a family thing
and Amazon has uh has done all the tests
they were successful on their first
attempt they have their own basic they
have everything that that Starling has
to put satellites into orbit in fact it
makes a lot more sense now I understand
the competition between Bezos and and
Elon and the reason is because they are
competing for infrastructure uh Bezos
has has widely been recognized as
someone who seeks to own the
infrastructure of our world and La he
actually tried to buy the streets at one
point he gets the he understands that if
you own the infrastructure you own
everything and he has completely
dominated the world of delivering
packages and goods to services to
everybody all out not to mention the the
delivery of goods and services directly
to Enterprises which Amazon spearheaded
in fact Bezos has is credited as having
created the term microservices and made
them the Enterprise standard for
architecture whether you like it or not
so when Amazon enters the ring for
competing against starlink for a low
earth
constellation orbit satellite Network
you want to pay attention so project
Kyer Kyper I think it is I think it's
somebody spell it right in the chat for
me because I can't remember how to spell
it they have got this really weird
spelling so in order K yeah Kyer thank
you so in order for this to get Kyer in
order for in order for the FCC to
approve it and I watched this in another
video there's another video called it's
got starlink in the name which why would
you put starlink I mean it sounds a
great Channel but why would you put
starlink in the name of your YouTube
channel and be permanently married to
starlink I think that's crazy that's
like calling your making your username
you know creeper 2000 or something and
having it forever be associated with
Minecraft I don't know why people would
do that but they did anyway in that
fantastic uh project Kyper is discussed
on the Starling Channel and he goes into
extreme detail with really great editing
I encourage you to go check it out do
the search for yourself and go find it
and
uh yeah Subaru system has been called
starlink which makes it impossible to do
any kind of searching for how to mount a
starlink on a Subaru I cannot find
anything to show that so the exciting
thing about this is that project kyber
from the very first day has had a mini
and their mini is 7 by7 in square and if
you can see if there's no other reason
for you to go watch that other channel
to see the picture of the mini that
Amazon has already been planning since
the very beginning go look at it not to
mention they are also planting a
starlink dish which is a round dish
which is only 10 in across it is much
much smaller than the Bas starlink model
and they also have an Enterprise model
which is about double the size of the
high performance flat dish but those are
the only three dishes those are the only
three antenna that they are planning on
releasing period they're not planning on
releasing anything else so that means
there is an interesting Gap there
because it looks like Amazon doesn't
care about the in motion Market it's
almost like they've given up on that
particular Market which is why I still
plan on getting the flat high
performance built for motion starlink
and and Amazon has also publicly stated
that they plan to first release
everything to the Enterprise customers
Enterprise customers are going to have
priority for the first year when is it
going to happen they in order for them
to qualify for the FCC ruling that says
yes you can put 3 34,000 constellation
based satellites up in in the up there
to fight with the Sterling satellites
they're literally going to be in the
same low earth over orbit you know in
order to do that they had to have it all
done by the end of this year so that
means the reason that the the reason
that the mini from the that that elon's
mini is getting released now is because
they are directly competing with what
project kyber has said it was going to
have no matter what yeah and and by the
way they those all those satellites lit
literally shoot lasers at each other in
order to maintain Communications with
one another they're already shooting
lasers at each
other all they have to do is turn up the
intensity of the laser and like oh
whoopsie we accidentally took out your
your mesh
Network seriously it's it's like it was
browser Wars and then it was like you
know internet Wars and now it's now it's
going to be literally lower satellite
constellation orbit Wars that are being
run by by Ai and this we haven't even we
don't even know about this stuff being
deployed in the Chinese and other people
that already have low earth over orbits
uh satellite constellation networks
whoever builds the first low Earth
satellite constellation Network that
beats out all the other ones wins and so
far Amazon's is better because it's
everybody everybody that's analyzing it
is like they've had a lot more time to
look at this thing they've had be
they've been able to to adapt to it
they've been able to see what what
mistakes you know starlink has made and
so it's really interesting but and
here's the kicker this is the single
biggest reason that anybody should care
about Amazon's re Amazon's version of
this Amazon has the has
AWS and starlink does not have that
Amazon already entirely controls they're
the single they're still the number one
provider of of microservices and you
know
purchasable Cloud sourced encrypted
sources they got their own version their
own outline version of Linux their own
version of sorry Evergreen Linux that
you can you know keep updated very
easily it upd auto updates itself and
everything they already dominated the
infrastructure Market they and they've
certainly dominated the Enterprise
infrastructure Market everybody's trying
to play catchup with Amazon you know you
could you could argue that Azure and you
know Google and and IBM they've all been
trying to catch up with Amazon with with
regard to selling infrastructure to
Enterprises and also to the common
person which came later so the thing
that's interesting about this is that
and this is this is a point that was
brought out by the Gentleman on this
other YouTube channel and I just want to
make sure I hit it really hard because
this is a big deal so these Enterprise
um starlink competitors are going to be
able to communicate endtoend fully
encrypted without the data ever touching
a non-private network starlink cannot do
that the only time the only way starlink
would ever be able to do that is if
starlink built its own Amazon web
services its own its own hosting hosting
services and starlink does not have the
resources to do that so
Amazon on the other hand does have
plenty of resources to compete with
starlink and sit there and let starlink
make all of its mistakes and make all of
its you know learn all its lessons for
it and then Amazon can say okay yeah
let's do that and then Amazon can can
deploy they have no lack there's no lack
of talent talent on the part of Amazon
to be able to keep up with Starling even
though the SpaceX is pretty damn cool
and there's great Engineers there I'm
not putting them down the point is is
that for us we win because of all the
competition that's happening but
Enterprises really win project Kyper
yeah so the the the Enterprises
themselves this is I mean think about
this right so you'll now have a
satellite linked Network that can
communicate at gigabit Ethernet speeds
that can that can communicate at giganet
ethernet speeds um available to any
company anywhere on the terrestrial
surface of the planet that has Vis
visual area of the sky just think about
how revolutionary that is this this this
is going to completely change the
socioeconomic and uh factors across the
globe and and Amazon is particularly
focused on poke on Enterprises and
companies and business we're going to
talk about the implications of of
business in general and how it gets done
and how it gets sourced later and for
digital Nomads but this is extremely
exciting if you can tell I'm super
excited by this because this means that
for the first time in history a company
can actually have a satellite-based
um uh satellite uh they can have a
satellite based
bpn think about that for a
second you guys know like like something
as simple as digital ocean right you get
a couple you spin up a couple droplets a
couple servers from digital ocean and
you know it's great right and you're
like well damn I want to do some stuff
on the back end I don't want this stuff
to be visible to the front end because I
don't know kubernetes I don't want to
expose my entire kubernetes network or
something so you want to have your own
private you know Network and then put a
public face on it that has an interface
like a rest interface or something like
that right so you would do that kind of
thing and and on digital ocean you just
you'd have a private so basically the V
virtual private Services being able to
run private safely encrypted non-exposed
can't get to them hosted servers that
can communicate with others of the same
system now see this is where things get
really really freaking interesting
Amazon has already been building an
onsite point of
presence on on the on the you know kind
of like oxide Computing has been doing
you get what I'm saying do you see where
all this is going I for the first time
ever I think I actually see where beos
is going with this and it's freaking
amazing I because what he's doing is
he's making it so that he can ship a a a
a physical point of presence anywhere in
the world couple that with an Enterprise
dish that's communicating a gigabit
speeds to the home base and have all of
it all of it integrated seamlessly with
existing AWS services and so that
everything in that business everything
in the business never touches the public
internet ever it doesn't touch it that
is a big deal that is a really big deal
that means that everything is going to
be able there there going to be able to
be businesses that run with models that
we've never even seen
before okay give me a second
there we go so what what I'm trying to
say I this is this is this if you're an
Enterprise architect and you don't know
about project kyber and and you are
responsible if you're a CTO and you're
responsible for deploying it skills all
across the globe things just got
extremely
interesting because now and I'm going to
make two conclusions on this video
because we're almost there I'm gonna
make two conclusions two really big
conclusions
that if you are a an Enterprise it
person or you're somebody who just wants
to build a company and you have there
are intelligent people all over the
world and particularly some place I
don't know like like um nagios right
there are places in the world that have
tremendous talent but have very they are
very underpaid and they're but they have
tremendous talent and skill and they
these people are now going to be
available resources that so think think
about that for a second I'm going to go
back here we'll turn it around I turn
off my thing for a second
here so so okay so so this is this is
way this is the way things are going
right and and I'll I'll try I got to
stop I'm going to over overheat in here
so so businesses are going to be able to
emerge that are going to be able to
leverage the best talent across the
globe and they're going to be able to
communicate and build up their entire it
infrastructure in the cloud and on
premises without having to ever have it
see the public now cloud computing has
already been a thing it's already the
biggest move my company my big huge
multinational company that I work for
which you would know by name please
don't say where it is um is also going
to be you know impacted by this they're
they're they obviously will be because
you know everything is moving to the
cloud and all that the cloud services
are still going to be there but the the
idea of being able to connect two
terrestrial points of press
through a gigabit Ethernet Cloud using
starlink or a starlink a starlink
competitor is going to be huge it's
going to be really huge and that kind of
that kind of thing is I I just don't
have I just don't have words for how how
big of a deal that is that's the first
conclusion that that this is going to
revolutionize I mean it really is this
is going I mean as as much as the
internet has
revolutionized everything and allow
digital being you know being a digital n
to be even a possibility or to have an
entire Workforce based in India or
Brazil or Italy or wherever right
wherever it's cheapest to get a digital
Workforce and right now I would say
probably 80% of our of the of the
resources that Supply you know it
resources people that supply that that
supply all the expertise they are not in
they are not in America they're not in
Europe the one of of the ones that are
working for the company that I work for
now which is really interesting um given
the company but so that's the first
thing the first thing is that this is
going to really seriously impact that um
and the SEC I mean the obvious one that
I should have mentioned is the first one
is that Amazon is pushing starlink hard
the fact that the fact that they're
going to have by the end of this year by
the end of this year there's going to be
an announcement from Amazon that they
have a mini and they always have it's
always been a part of their original
plan and they're going to end up they're
going to end up producing a mini that's
better and lower priced than the mini
that is already being used that's been
that's been touted by starlink so so
this is fantastic for us that's probably
the biggest thing the second biggest
thing is the ability to to run
businesses completely completely in ways
that we've never even thought of that
are going to change the business model
across the board that for the better
it's going to more space trash hell yeah
there's going to be more space rash and
the third the third thing and this is
the one that I care about is that I'm
going to be able to get a mini from
Amazon that's a fraction of the cost of
the mini that's being sold by by um
uh Mr Elon Musk and his SpaceX people so
my concern is about whether the mini is
going to be available yet I don't know
you guys know but in this storage unit
right here I have a Burly trailer and
I'm I have a perfect place to put a a
mini a mini starlink which is I looked
at the high performance one I'm
realizing my high performance dish is
not going to easily fit on my trailer
for my bike but it will but next year
there's going to be they're going to be
they're going to be you know Amazon's
going to be rolling this out first
Enterprise which means we're probably
two years away from having
uh the mini but the SpaceX might be
pushed to let us have their mini first
the bottom line is that that mini is
going to allow us to to be on our bikes
and go bike packing and have and have
and that's going to be really the way to
go everybody's going to be doing it
every IRL streamer is probably already
eyeing this I'm I'm surprised some of
them haven't already gotten early access
to it um given you know all the people
that they know but but in my case I
don't know anybody so you know I'm going
to wait so what does this mean for me
this means that I'm actually very very
happily
um my I'm very happy with my my order of
the um high performance flat Starling
dish which is 20 20 by 21 in and that's
going to fit on top of my car it does
mean that I'm going to probably seek to
have it permanently installed on the car
this is why I'm making a video right now
because I've been going back and forth
about do I want this to be temporary do
I want to be able to pull it off of the
car do I want it to be bolted on you
know how how do I want to go about this
so I want to be able to put this thing
on my trailer and the answer is right
now that I just want it to enable use on
the car that's it that's it and I can
wait I can wait for another two years or
whatever it takes to get a mini and I'll
put the mini on the trailer and the mini
will draw a lot less power it's the kind
of thing that I can power completely
from solar and and the weight is way the
the mini the mini weighs
5bs yeah the mini the mini from Amazon
weighs 5 lbs it's 7 by s in it weighs 5
lbs it looks like a nice little coffee
desks it looks like a nice little I
don't know kind of silk sculpture right
next to your laptop when you're working
on room but whe can you move with it or
not I don't know I don't care most of
the time when I'm doing things it's
probably not going to be mo in motion
and and the places that I go most of
those places are going to be served
pretty well by just Verizon or whatever
it is uh for most of the trip and then
those few times when I want to make camp
and say hey I did this thing and instead
of live streaming it while I'm doing it
if if I and I could probably live stream
uh you know bike trips that are closer
to to Verizon and you know range and all
that stuff so so that's that's it this
is a very messy video um I don't make
organized videos um the company to clean
up the trash
yeah there's going to be there's going
to be a lot of trash up there and and
but but as we go through you know little
what do we want satellite Wars we'll
call it satellite Wars so this I I think
it's really exciting um I think it's I
think the biggest takeaway for most of
the people watching this particular
you're an IRL person is that you should
wait for the mini bottom line bottom
line I think I think everybody should
wait for the mini they are lower price
they're less weight they're lower power
and they are easy they're easier to to
Port P around the only people that are
going to want the bigger the bigger
things are going to be people that are
moving which you know you could argue
most rvers don't even really want that
they just want a really solid connection
once they get there and the and and the
residential people the residential
people are going to want to have
something very reliable that works no
matter what even when there's clouds and
storm you know whatever is going to
happen there that those those bases are
already covered by starlink and they're
going to also be covered by um by by K
project kyber whatever you say however
you say it so pay attention to that save
your money um but again the takeaway for
me is I'm going to invest all in on the
high performance flat dish because as of
the as of today based on what I learned
about that project it is very important
that
that starlink focus on the in motion
dish because they have an edge over them
Amazon is focusing on getting in the
Enterprise customers and linking them up
with virtual private networks or act not
virtual private networks actual private
networks these aren't virtual private
these are real actual private networks
because they control all the components
from one point to the other on
infrastructure these are not virtual
private networks these are real private
networks so they don't have the overhead
of a a virtual private Network which is
going to make Amazon is definitely just
going to destroy the rest of the field
when it comes to Enterprise deployments
of satellite linking and architecture
and stuff like that and that's what
they're shooting for they've said so so
that means starlink is going to be still
be pushing for the Common Man or
whatever and and then that means they're
going to they're they give they care
more about people that are moving so um
yeah buiness already has it they've
already launched it they've already
Amazon has already put stuff into orbit
and they already have their own rocket
ships for this they already have their
own terrestrial land stations they've
already tested everything the only thing
they're doing now is they're building
out they're bu they're building up the
satellites that they've already tested
and got to work right so that's what's
coming up